<Defs>
	<!-- Muzzle -->
	<Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef ParentName="WolfJawBase">
		<defName>EtherRedWolfMuzzle</defName>
		<label>red wolf muzzle</label>
		<description>Following exposure to mutagenic mechanites, a slender red wolf snout has replaced this pawn's face completely with a set of fangs and pointed teeth.  It's perfect for biting and tearing through meat, but depending on the exact form the mutation has taken it may severely hampen their ability to speak.
		
Wolves are known for hunting with their teeth and not their claws, and wolfmorphs are no different.  With practice, red wolf morphs can use their muzzles to harry their opponents in battle to create openings, which more than makes up for any difficulties they may have at wielding weapons with inflexible paws.</description>
		<classInfluence>RedWolfMorph</classInfluence>
		<mutationTale>GrewCanidMuzzle</mutationTale>
		<mutationMemory>RedWolfMuzzleMemory</mutationMemory>
		<graphics>
			<MuzzleMale>Parts/WolfRed/RedWolf_Jaw</MuzzleMale>
			<MuzzleFemale>Parts/WolfRed/RedWolf_Jaw</MuzzleFemale>
		</graphics>
		<stagePatches>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>growing</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s face has grown into a stubby animal muzzle.  [PAWN_possessive] teeth are starting to grow out into fangs, and the skin of [PAWN_possessive] nose has grown black and rough.  It's still too short to bite effectively, though.</description>
				</li>
				<li function="modify">
					<stageKey>adapting</stageKey>
					<description>A slender, red wolf snout graces [PAWN_nameDef]'s face, completely with a set of fangs and pointed teeth -- perfect for biting with.  The tongue and lips retain some humanlike flexibility which allows [PAWN_objective] a rough form of speech, though it'll take [PAWN_objective] some time to get used to it.</description>
					<statOffsets>
						<MeleeHitChance>+1.20</MeleeHitChance>
					</statOffsets>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>adapted</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>A slender, red wolf snout graces [PAWN_nameDef]'s face, completely with a set of fangs and pointed teeth -- perfect for biting with, especially now that [PAWN_pronoun]'s had some practice.  The tongue and lips retain some humanlike flexibility allowing [PAWN_objective] a passable (if growly) form of speech now that [PAWN_pronoun] has gotten used to it.</description>
					<statOffsets>
						<MeleeHitChance>+2.20</MeleeHitChance>
					</statOffsets>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>paragon</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>A slender, red wolf snout graces [PAWN_nameDef]'s face, completely with a set of fangs and pointed teeth -- perfect for biting with.  The mechanites have made further modifications and have managed to subtly blend elements of human anatomy into the otherwise-lupine muzzle, allowing [PAWN_objective] to speak and express [PAWN_possessive]self as well as any human despite it.  While [PAWN_nameDef]'s wolfish face may not be beautiful in the traditional sense, the perfectly-sculpted wolf muzzle and head now lends [PAWN_objective] a certain elegance.</description>
					<statOffsets>
						<Beauty>+0.50</Beauty>
						<MeleeHitChance>+2.20</MeleeHitChance>
					</statOffsets>
				</values>
			</li>
		</stagePatches>
	</Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef>

	<!-- Ears -->
	<Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef ParentName="WolfEarPart">
		<defName>EtherRedWolfEar</defName>
		<label>red wolf ear</label>
		<description>A large, fuzzy ear that belongs to a red wolf, which has found its way onto this (un)fortunate pawn through the application of mutagenic mechanites.  It can hear much better than a normal human ear, and some say it looks cute too.</description>
		<classInfluence>RedWolfMorph</classInfluence>
		<mutationTale>EarsChangedCanid</mutationTale>
		<mutationMemory>RedWolfEarMemory</mutationMemory>
		<graphics>
			<LeftEar>Parts/RedWolf/RedWolf_Ear_Left</LeftEar>
			<LeftEarBehind>Parts/RedWolf/RedWolf_Ear_Left_Behind</LeftEarBehind>
			<RightEar>Parts/RedWolf/RedWolf_Ear_Right</RightEar>
			<RightEarBehindHead>Parts/RedWolf/RedWolf_Ear_Right_Behind</RightEarBehindHead>
		</graphics>
		<stagePatches>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>initial</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s ear is longer and noticably pointed, making [PAWN_objective] look a bit like an elf.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>pressing</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s ear is growing flatter and even pointier -- like an animal's -- and has begun to migrate toward the top of [PAWN_possessive] head.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>growing</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s ear is now triangular and sits atop [PAWN_possessive] head.  It has started to twitch and move in response to both sounds and [PAWN_nameDef]'s emotions, much to [PAWN_possessive] annoyance.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>grown</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>A large, fuzzy red wolf ear crowns [PAWN_nameDef]'s head, flicking and turning independently at the slightest sound of prey.  It tends to fold back any time [PAWN_nameDef] finds [PAWN_objective]self nervous or uncertain.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
		</stagePatches>
	</Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef>

	<!-- Tail -->
	<Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef ParentName="WolfTailPart">
		<defName>EtherRedWolfTail</defName>
		<label>red wolf tail</label>
		<description>Due to exposure to mutagenic mechanites, this pawn now has a tail that would ordinarily belong to a red wolf.  It's not good for much other than betraying its owner's mood, but it does slightly help them balance -- especially in the midst of combat.</description>
		<classInfluence>RedWolfMorph</classInfluence>
		<mutationTale>GrewTail</mutationTale>
		<mutationMemory>RedWolfTailMemory</mutationMemory>
		<graphics>
			<Tail>Parts/RedWolf/RedWolf_Tail</Tail>
		</graphics>
		<stagePatches>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<stageKey>initial</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>A small tail has started to grow from [PAWN_nameDef]'s backside.  It's still just a nub for now, but pretty soon [PAWN_pronoun] is going to need to cut a tail-hole in [PAWN_possessive] pants.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>pressing</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s growing tail is now short and slender, and is developing into a canid shape.  It's long enough to make wearing pants awkward but not quite long enough to be useful.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>growing</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s tail is reaching its full length, and has started to wag and emote.  It's cute, but it tends to betray [PAWN_possessive] mood at the worst times.</description>
					<statOffsets>
						<TradePriceImprovement>-0.10</TradePriceImprovement>
						<MentalBreakThreshold>-0.0375</MentalBreakThreshold>
						<HuntingStealth>+0.05</HuntingStealth>
					</statOffsets>
				</values>
			</li>
			<li function="modify">
				<stageKey>grown</stageKey>
				<values>
					<description>A slender red wolf-like tail hangs from [PAWN_nameDef]'s spine.  It's cute, and now that [PAWN_nameDef] has gotten used to it, it no longer gives away [PAWN_possessive] mood during trading or poker night.</description>
				</values>
			</li>
		</stagePatches>
	</Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef>
	
	<!-- Eyes -->
	<Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef ParentName="RedWolfPart">
		<defName>EtherRedWolfEye</defName>
		<label>lupine</label>
		<description>Golden- or orange-colored wolf eyes with a large, black-ringed iris.  They look striking, especially on a mutated human, but alas they are red-green colorblind.  They also have inferior visual acuity compared to a human's eyes, but they're well adapted to noticing motion.  A morph with these eyes will suffer at most vision-related tasks but once they adapt to the specialized senses they will fare better in melee combat than a baseline human.</description>
		<mutationMemory>RedWolfEyeMemory</mutationMemory>
		<stages>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<labelOverride>golden</labelOverride>
				<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s eyes are turning gold.  Striking, but so far the change doesn't seem to have any practical effect.</description>
			</li>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<minSeverity>0.1</minSeverity>
				<labelOverride>golden (colorblind)</labelOverride>
				<description>[PAWN_nameDef]'s eyes have lost their ability to differentiate red and green as they become increasingly wolflike.</description>
				<partEfficiencyOffset>-0.15</partEfficiencyOffset>
			</li>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<minSeverity>0.25</minSeverity>
				<description>[PAWN_nameDef] now has a striking set of gold-colored wolf eyes.  They're quite intimidating, but alas [PAWN_pronoun] is now red-green colorblind and can't quite see fine details as well.  With some practice, [PAWN_pronoun] should be able to partially adapt.</description>
				<partEfficiencyOffset>-0.30</partEfficiencyOffset>
			</li>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<minSeverity>0.5</minSeverity>
				<label>partially adapted</label>
				<description>[PAWN_nameDef] now has a striking set of gold-colored wolf eyes.  They're quite intimidating, but alas [PAWN_pronoun] is now red-green colorblind and can't quite see fine details as well.  [PAWN_pronoun] has gotten somewhat used to them, though [PAWN_pronoun] doesn't have enough experience to make the most of them yet.</description>
				<partEfficiencyOffset>-0.20</partEfficiencyOffset>
				<statOffsets>
					<MeleeHitChance>+1.2</MeleeHitChance>
					<MeleeDodgeChance>+0.6</MeleeDodgeChance>
				</statOffsets>
			</li>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<minSeverity>1</minSeverity>
				<label>adapted</label>
				<description>[PAWN_nameDef] now has a striking set of gold-colored wolf eyes.  They're quite intimidating, but alas [PAWN_pronoun] is now red-green colorblind.  [PAWN_possessive] fine detail vision suffers, but the extra motion sensitivity gives [PAWN_objective] a better sense of [PAWN_possessive] prey's movement when hunting.</description>
				<partEfficiencyOffset>-0.20</partEfficiencyOffset>
				<statOffsets>
					<MeleeHitChance>+1.7</MeleeHitChance>
					<MeleeDodgeChance>+0.8</MeleeDodgeChance>
				</statOffsets>
			</li>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationStage">
				<minSeverity>1.25</minSeverity>
				<label>paragon</label>
				<description>[PAWN_nameDef] now has a striking set of gold-colored wolf eyes.  They're quite intimidating, and thanks to further adaption by the mechanites, have regained tri-color vision.  They're still not quite as good as human eyes at seeing fine details, but in exchange they retain the extra motion sensitivity of wolf eyes combined with the color vision of human ones.  This gives [PAWN_objective] an overwhelming advantage against [PAWN_possessive] prey when hunting.</description>
				<partEfficiencyOffset>-0.05</partEfficiencyOffset>
				<statOffsets>
					<MeleeHitChance>+1.8</MeleeHitChance>
					<MeleeDodgeChance>+1.2</MeleeDodgeChance>
				</statOffsets>
			</li>
		</stages>
		<comps>
			<li Class="Pawnmorph.Hediffs.CompProperties_MutationSeverityAdjust">
				<severityPerDay>0.25</severityPerDay>
			</li>
		</comps>
		<parts>
			<li>Eye</li>
		</parts>
		<categories>
			<li>Major</li>
		</categories>
	</Pawnmorph.Hediffs.MutationDef>
</Defs>
